[ Helicopter Approaching ]
[ Cocks Gun ]
[ Fires Gun ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Whirring ]
[ Guitar ]
[ Electronic Beeping ]
[ Female Computer Voice ] Your move : Bishop to knight four .
- My move : Knight to rook three . - [ Chuckles ]
- [ Computer Beeps ] - Poor baby , you 're startin to lose it , aren 't ya ?
[ Buzzes ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Computer ] Your move : King to rook one .
[ Beeps ] My move : Rook to knight six .
Checkmate . Checkmate . [ Beeping ]
- [ Sizzling ] - You cheating ' bitch .
[ Gunshots ]
[ Gunshots Continue , Helicopter Approaching ]
[ Helicopter Circling ]
Childs , what 's he doin ' ?
Circlin ' the camp .
Who is he ?
- Said Norge or something on the side . - That 's Norwegian .
[ Helicopter Approaching ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Shouting Norwegian ]
[ Norwegian ]
[ Norwegian Continues ]
[ Shouting Norwegian , Fires Rifle ]
- [ Groan ] - [ Shouting Norwegian ]
[ Gunman Shouting , Continues Shooting ]
[ Breaking Glass ]
[ Gunshots Ricochet ]
- George , are you okay ? - Yeah , yeah , I 'm okay .
Yeah . What 's goin ' on down there ?
[ Men Running ]
Watch it !
[ Indistinct Talking ]
[ Approaching Footsteps ]
[ Man Talking Softly ] Easy .
Easy . Easy .
Easy . Yes .
[ Fire Extinguisher Spraying , Men Coughing ]
First goddamn week of winter .
[ Coughing Continues ]
[ Groaning ]
Oh , come on . Four stitches . Barely grazed ya .
What were they doing flying that low ,
- shooting at a dog , at us ? - Hmm , stir-crazy ,
cabin fever , who knows ?
U.S. Number 31 , calling McMurdo . Come in , over .
[ Clicking , Static ]
U.S. Number 31 , calling McMurdo , urgent ! Come in , over .
- [ Clicking , Static ] - Great .
- [ Man ] Come on , come on . - Nobody !
Nobody ? Get ahold of somebody . Get ahold of anybody ! We gotta report this mess !
Look , I haven 't been able to reach shit in two weeks !
I doubt if anybody 's talked to anybody on this entire continent ,
and you want me to reach somebody !
Maybe we at war with Norway .
I was wondering when El Capitan was gonna get a chance to use his popgun .
- How long they been stationed there ? - It says here only eight weeks .
- [ Officer ] That 's not long enough for guys to go bonkers . - Bullshit , Bwana .
Five minutes is enough to put a man over down here .
- [ Man ] Damn straight . - I mean , look at Palmer .
He been the way he is since the first day .
- How many in their party ? - They started with ten .
- There 'd be eight others left . - How do we know ?
Guys as crazy as that could have done a lot of damage to their own before they got to us .
- Nothing we can do . - Oh , yes there is . I want to go up .
- In this weather ? - Bennings ?
- Winds are gonna let up a tad next couple of hours . - A tad ?
Can 't condone it much myself , but it is a short haul .
An hour there , an hour back .
- Shit , Doc , I 'll give you the lift . No problem . - Forget it , Palmer .
Thanks for thinkin about it though .
Loaded with kerosene . I count 15 cans .
- MacReady ! - Mac , get your gear on .
- It may not clear up for a week , and we 're the closest to ' em . - It 's all right by me , Doc .
- I 'm just letting you know we 're taking a chance . - Quit griping , MacReady .
If we get caught in a white-out , you can scratch one doctor and one pilot .
This is real thin . It 'll clear as soon as you get up .
It 's up to you , Mac .
If you don 't wanna fly , we don 't fly .
- You really wanna save those crazy Swedes , huh ? - [ Doc ] Norwegians .
- Which way , Doc ? - Southwest .
You have to read the map 'cause I 'm gonna be busy .
[ Helicopter Engine Humming ]
Mac 's really taking it up , huh ? [ Sighs ]
[ Palmer ] He knows what he 's doing .
[ " Superstition " ]
Nauls , will you turn that crap down ? I 'm trying to get some sleep . I was shot today .
- Oui , Bwana . Will do . - Very superstitious
[ Roller Skates Gliding ]
Writing 's on the wall
Very superstitious
[ Continues ]
Anybody there ?
Hey , Sweden ?
They 're not Swedish , Mac , they 're Norwegian .
Mac !
My God ! What the hell happened here ?
Come on , Doc .
[ Sighs ] Portable video unit .
- Anything ? - It 's all in Norwegian .
[ Papers Rustling ]
- What are ya doin ' , Doc ? - It could be important work . I wanna take it back with us .
It 's gettin ' late . Let 's hurry it up .
I 'll check out the last few rooms .
[ MacReady ] Hey , Copper , come here !
Maybe they found a fossil , the remains of some animal buried in the ice ,
- and they chopped it out . - But where is it ? Look at this .
[ Copper ] What is that ?
Is that a man in there or something ?
Whatever it is , they burned it up in a hurry .
Help me find a shovel , Doc .
- We found this . - Jesus Christ !
[ Gagging ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
[ Copper ] Blair , I 'd like you to start an autopsy right away .
[ Coughing ]
- [ Loud Feedback ] - [ Screams ]
- Did you reach anybody yet ? - Reach anybody ?
We 're a thousand miles from nowhere , man ,
and it 's gonna get a hell of a lot worse before it gets any better !
Well , stick to it , Windows , stick to it .
Nothin ' wrong with this Norwegian , physiologically anyway .
- No drugs , no alcohol , nothin ' . - Hmm .
[ Sniffing ]
Well , what we got here is what appears to be , anyway ,
a normal set of internal organs .
Heart ,
lungs , kidneys , liver ,
intestines .
Seem to be normal .
[ Monty Hall ] ... one , door number two and door number three .
I think that Dawn Screen here has got the most to trade in . I went to you first .
You brought your friend , Anna . You 've been consulting Anna all through the show .
- You may as well consult her one more time . - I know how this one ends .
[ Jukebox Playing " Don 't Explain " ]
[ Screams ]
Clark , will you put this mutt with the others where it belongs ?
Yeah , okay .
[ Sighs ]
- [ Unlatches Door ] - Go ahead .
Go ahead . What are you waiting for ?
[ Closes , Latches Door ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Deep Inhalation , Exhalation ]
- [ Snarling ] - [ Barking ]
[ Dog Groaning , Thing Screeches ]
[ Barking ]
[ Tentacle Buzzing ]
[ Tentacles Buzzing ]
[ Dogs Barking ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
[ Limbs Snapping ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Dogs Howling , Barking ]
[ Banging Against Fence ]
[ Barking , Howling Continues ]
[ Dogs Yelping , Whining ]
[ Buzzing ]
- [ Slams Door Closed ] - [ Thing Screeching ]
[ Distant Howling , Whimpering ]
[ Shatters Glass , Alarm Blaring ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
I don 't know what the hell 's in there .
- It 's weird and pissed off , whatever it is . - Bennings , go get Childs .
[ Windows ] What is this ? What 's goin ' on ?
- Hey , Palmer , what is this ? - I don 't know .
Childs ! Mac wants the flamethrower !
- Mac wants the what ? - That 's what he said !
- Now , move ! - Damn it !
[ Dogs Whimpering , Whining , Thing Roaring ]
[ Whimpering Continues ]
- Stand back . - Mac , what is it ?
- [ Barking ] - [ Panting ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Continues Screeching ]
[ Whining ]
- [ Shrieks ] - [ Gunshots Continue ]
- [ Gunshot Blast , Yelps ] - No ! No ! God !
- Don 't ! Don 't ! No ! - Get back ! Get back !
- Get your ass over here ! Burn it ! - [ Thing Roaring ]
Damn it , Childs , torch it !
[ Screeching ]
[ Man Coughing ]
Oh , my God .
Oh ! Ohh !
Look . Son of a bitch .
[ Groans ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Blair ] What we 're talking about here is an organism ...
that imitates other life-forms , and it imitates them perfectly .
When this thing attacked our dogs ,
it tried to digest ' em , absorb them .
And in the process shape its own cells to imitate them .
This , for instance . That 's not dog .
It 's imitation .
We got to it before it had time to finish .
Finish what ?
Finish imitating these dogs .
Easy . Easy . Good .
- Easy . Easy . - [ Clanging ]
- [ Sighs ] Clark ? - Yeah ?
Did you notice anything strange about the dog , anything at all ?
Strange ? No .
What was the dog doing in the rec room ?
I don 't know .
He was just wandering around camp all day .
Are you sayin ' to me the dog wasn 't put in the kennel until last night ?
- Right . - How long were you alone with that dog ?
I don 't know , an hour , hour and a half maybe .
What the hell you lookin at me like that for ?
- I don 't know . - What ?
I don 't know . It 's probably nothing ' .
It 's nothin ' at all .
How much more of this crap is there ?
- Oh , nine hours I 'd say . - We can 't learn anything from this .
[ Officer ] Guess not .
Where 'd they take these shots ?
Seems like they were spending a lot of their time ...
in a little place northeast of their camp about five or six miles .
[ Officer ] What 's that ?
[ MacReady ] It looks like something buried under the ice .
[ Bennings ] And look at that , they 're planting thermite charges .
[ Officer ] Whatever it was , it was bigger than the block of ice you found .
Here .
This is it , the place where they were spending most of their time .
- Pretty nasty out . 35 knots . - Screw it . I 'm gonna go up anyway .
Half a mile due east .
Jesus ! How long you figure this has been in the ice ?
Well , the backscatter effect 's been bringin ' things up ...
from way down around here for a long time .
I 'd say ... I 'd say the ice it 's buried in ...
is 100,000 years old at least .
- And those Norwegians blew it up . - Yeah .
[ MacReady Sighs ] I don 't know .
Thousands of years ago it crashes and this thing ...
gets thrown out or crawls out and it ends up freezing in the ice .
- I just cannot believe any of this voodoo bullshit . - [ Palmer ] Childs ,
happens all the time , man .
They 're fallin out of the skies like flies .
Government knows all about it . Right , Mac ?
- Do you believe any of this voodoo bullshit , Blair ? - [ Palmer ] Childs ?
Childs , Chariots Of The Gods , man .
They practically own South America .
I mean , they taught the Incas everything they know .
[ Clinks ]
So , come on now , MacReady .
The Norwegians get ahold of this ...
- and they dig it up out of the ice . - Yes , Garry , they dig it up ,
they cart it back , it gets thawed out ,
wakes up , probably not in the best of moods .
- I don 't know ... - Which one of you disrespectful men ...
been tossin ' his dirty drawers in the kitchen trash can , huh ?
From now on , I want my kitchen clean , all right ? Germ free !
Now , how 's this motherfucker wake up after thousands of years in the ice ?
- And how can it look like a dog ? - [ MacReady ] I don 't know how .
'Cause it 's different than us , see .
'Cause it 's from outer space . What do you want from me ? Ask him .
You buy any of this , Blair ?
[ Typing , Ticking ]
[ Copper On Intercom ] Mac , we 're movin ' those things ...
out of the lab into the storeroom .
Can you come get your stuff ?
Be there in a minute , Doc .
Through the door .
Right over there . Right over there .
[ Groaning ]
Sorry , Mac . You have to move your stuff ...
Doc says we gotta stash ' em in here and lock ' em up .
- I have to talk to you . - I 'm tired of talking , Fuchs .
I just want to get up to my shack and get drunk .
- Mac , it 's important . - What is it ?
- Outside . - It 's 40 below outside .
In the Thiokol . Please , Mac .
[ Windows ] We ought to just burn these things .
Can 't burn the find of the century .
That 's gonna win somebody the Nobel Prize .
You got the keys ?
Get ' em from Garry . I want to get some stuff out of here .
There 's something wrong with Blair .
He 's locked in his room and won 't answer the door .
- I took one of his notebooks from the lab . Listen . - Yeah ?
" It could have imitated a million life-forms on a million planets .
It could change into any one of them at any time .
- Now it wants life-forms on Earth ... " - It 's gettin ' cold ,
- and I haven 't slept in two days . - Wait a minute , Mac .
" It needs to be alone and in close proximity with the life-form to be absorbed .
- The chameleon strikes in the dark . " - Is Blair cracking up ?
Damn it , MacReady . " There 's still cellular activity in these burned remains .
They 're not dead yet . "
Let 's go , Bennings . I gotta get some sleep .
Holy shit .
[ Drops Keys ]
Go get the doc .
- I 'll get Garry . We 'll meet in Blair 's room . - All right .
It 's Bennings !
[ Windows ] Bennings was right there , Mac ! I swear it had ahold of him !
[ Alarm Blaring ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
- Windows , get back ! Keep away from him ! - Don 't touch him !
Get back ! Stay back !
[ MacReady ] It isn 't Bennings !
[ Roars ]
[ Roaring Continues ]
[ Roaring ]
- My God ! What was happening to him ? - If it had time to finish ,
it would have looked and sounded and acted just like Bennings !
- I don 't know what you 're saying . - That was one of those things ,
trying to imitate him , Garry .
- Come on . - MacReady , I 've known Bennings for ten years .
He 's my friend .
We gotta burn the rest of them .
All right , step back .
You sure that 's all of ' em ?
We cleaned out the storehouse , the lab .
There is nothing left .
Where 's Blair ?
[ Engine Stops ]
I can 't find Blair .
Where 's everybody else ?
Windows is in the radio room still trying to get through .
Everyone else is in the rec room .
You go on . I 'll be in in a minute .
[ Metal Clinking ]
Blair ?
[ Sets Down Flamethrower ]
[ Electrical Sparking ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Blair ] Don 't come in here ! I got a gun ! I got an ax !
Don 't , you son of a bitch ! Don 't come in here ! You understand me ?
- He 's got a gun , Mac ! - Anybody interferes , I 'll kill ' im !
- [ Bullet Ricochets ] - Jesus !
- [ Blair Yelling Indistinctly ] - He smashed up some of the chopper pretty good .
Childs , go see if he got to the tractor .
[ Clanging , Yelling ] Nobody gets in and out of here ! Nobody !
You guys think I 'm crazy ! Well , that 's fine !
Most of ya don 't know what 's going on around here !
But I 'm damn well sure some of you do !
Christ !
He got most of the chopper and the tractor , and he 's killed the rest of the dogs .
[ Clanging Continues ]
Garry , wait a minute ! Wait a minute !
All right , Childs , go around to the map room door ,
- talk to him . - Okay .
Go on .
Norris , get a table from the lab .
- [ Glass Shattering ] - Do you think that thing wanted to be an animal ?
No dogs make it a thousand miles through the cold .
[ Glass Shattering ]
No , you don 't understand !
That thing wanted to be us !
A cell gets out , it could imitate everything on the face of the earth !
- [ Blair ] And nothing could stop it ! - Okay , Blair ,
come on now , you don 't want to hurt anybody .
- [ Bullet Ricochets ] - I 'll kill you !
- [ Gunshots ] - [ Empty Gun Clicks ]
[ Blair Yells ]
[ Yells ]
[ Blair Groaning ]
Good shot , MacReady . Excuse me .
- All right , bring him up . Lift him up . - Yeah .
- [ Grunting ] - Okay . Okay .
Come on , Blair .
- What about your shack , MacReady ? - I don 't want him in my shack .
We 'll lock him in the toolshed .
[ Hammering ]
Why am I in here ?
For your own protection , Blair ... and ours .
How you doin ' , old boy ?
I don 't know who to trust .
[ Swallowing ] I know what you mean , Blair .
Trust is a tough thing to come by these days .
Tell you what ,
why don 't you just trust in the Lord ?
Watch Clark .
What ?
I said , " Watch Clark . "
And watch him close , do you hear me ?
[ Door Closing , Locking ]
[ Garry ] Now the radio 's gone .
- So are the choppers . - We 're completely cut off .
All we can do now is hole up ' til spring and wait for the rescue team .
No , we don 't wait . Somebody in this camp ain 't what he appears .
Right now that may be one or two of us . By spring it could be all of us .
So how do we know who 's human ?
If I was an imitation ... a perfect imitation ...
how would you know if it was really me ?
Is there some kind of test , Doc ?
Well , yeah ... possibly .
- I 've been thinking about a blood serum test . - [ Garry ] What 's that ?
We could take a sample of each person 's blood .
We could mix it with uncontaminated blood .
I suppose if there 's a reaction , we 'd know who isn 't human .
We 've got whole blood in storage .
Here , start working on it . [ Keys Jingling ]
Keep an eye on Clark .
He was close to that dog .
[ Garry ] Yeah . Yeah .
Mac , we need Blair 's help . He 's the only one ...
- who knows what this organism is capable of . - He 's too far gone , Fuchs .
But get the rest of his notebooks and start going through them .
[ Copper ] Garry ! Hey , you guys , come here !
What ?
- Somebody got to the blood ! - What ?
- Where 's Clark ? - Right here .
Wait a minute , wait a minute . Was this broken into ?
No , the lock is undamaged .
- Somebody opened it , closed it , then locked it . - [ Windows ] Great .
Who 's got access to it ?
I guess I 'm the only one .
And I got the only key .
Would that test have worked , Doc ?
- Oh , I think so , yes . - [ Norris ] Somebody else sure as hell thought so .
Well , who else could have used that key ?
Nobody ! I just give it to Copper whenever he needs it !
- Could anybody have gotten it from you , Doc ? - I don 't see how .
As soon as I 'm finished , I return it right away .
Great .
- [ Childs ] When was the last time you used it ? - [ Copper ] A day or so ago .
I suppose somebody could have lifted it off me ...
Oh , come on ! That key ring is always hooked to your belt .
- [ Indistinct Shouting ] - Accusing everybody ...
[ MacReady ] Stop it now ! It ain 't worth it !
- Copper 's the only one who 's got any business with it . - [ Copper ] Wait a minute !
- You 've been in here on several occasions ! - Doc thought of the test .
- That clears him ? Bullshit ! - Why would he take ...
- [ MacReady ] Shut up , man ! - Windows ! - Windows !
[ Cocks Pistol ] Put that down .
- No . - I 'll put this right through your head .
You guys gonna listen to Garry , let him give the orders ?
He could be one of those things !
Windows , wait a minute . Just take it easy .
Put the gun down . Put it down .
- Garry , you don 't want to hurt anybody . - Get back .
[ Garry ] On the floor .
[ Drops Rifle ]
It 's on the floor .
I don 't know about Copper ,
but I give you my word , I did not go near that blood .
[ Uncocks Pistol ]
But I guess you 'll all feel a little easier ...
if somebody else was in charge .
Norris , I can 't see anybody objecting to you .
I 'm sorry , fellas , but I-I-I 'm not up to it .
- I 'll take it . - Like hell you will .
It should be somebody a little more even tempered , Childs .
[ Sighs ]
[ Garry ] All right .
[ Wind Howling ]
[ MacReady ] I know I 'm human .
And if you were all these things , then you 'd just attack me right now .
So some of you are still human .
This thing doesn 't want to show itself .
It wants to hide inside an imitation .
It 'll fight if it has to ,
but it 's vulnerable out in the open .
If it takes us over ,
then it has no more enemies ,
nobody left to kill it .
And then it 's won .
There 's a storm hitting us in six hours .
We 're gonna find out who 's who .
All right , Doc , Garry and Clark move over there away from the others .
Norris , you and Childs shoot ' em up with morphine . Tie ' em down and watch ' em .
- Fuchs , you start workin ' on a new test . - I need Doc 's help .
Yeah , you don 't want to drug me .
Mac , I 'm not a prisoner !
Here , let me do it . You 're gonna break the needle in my arm .
[ Childs ] No , Doc . He 's doin ' a real fine job .
[ Groans ]
I 'm gonna hide this tape when I 'm finished .
If none of us make it , at least there 'll be some kind of record .
Storm 's been hitting us hard now for 48 hours .
We still have nothing to go on .
One other thing .
I think it rips through your clothes when it takes you over .
Windows found some shredded long johns , but the name tag was missing .
They could be anybody 's .
Nobody ...
Nobody trusts anybody now .
And we 're all very tired .
[ Tape Rewinding ]
Nobody trusts anybody now .
There 's nothing else I can do .
Just wait .
- R.J. MacReady , helicopter pilot , U.S. Outpost Number 31 . - [ Clicks Off Recorder ]
You come up with anything yet ?
One or two ideas .
[ Sighs ]
But , MacReady , I 've been thinking .
If a small particle of this thing is enough to take over an entire organism ,
then everyone should prepare their own meals .
I suggest we only eat out of cans .
All right .
[ Kicks Metal Object , Indistinct Buzzing ]
Who 's that ?
Anybody see Fuchs ?
Somebody blew out a fuse in the lab .
Lights were out for an hour . Any one of us could have gotten to him .
All right , we gotta find him .
Nauls , why don 't you come with me and we 'll look outside .
Palmer , you and Windows check the inside .
I ain 't goin ' with Windows .
I ain 't goin ' with him . I 'll go with Childs .
- Hey , fuck you , Palmer ! - I ain 't goin ' with you !
- [ Childs ] Who says I want you goin ' with me ? - All right , cut the bullshit !
Windows , you come with us . Norris , you stay here .
Any of them move , you fry ' em . You hear anything at all , you cut loose on the sirens .
We all meet back here in 20 minutes , regardless !
And everybody watch whoever you 're with ,
real close .
Hey , Blair !
Blair , have you seen Fuchs ?
I don 't want to stay out here anymore .
I want to come back inside .
Funny things . I hear funny things out here .
- Have you come across Fuchs ? - It ain 't Fuchs .
It ain 't Fuchs .
I 'm not gonna harm anybody , and there 's nothing wrong with me .
And if there was , I 'm all better now .
I 'd like to come back inside . You got my promise .
We 'll see .
Hey , wait a minute . Wait a minute , man .
I want to come back inside . Don 't you understand ?
I 'm all right . I 'm much better . I won 't harm anybody .
You gotta let me come back inside .
Hold it !
Is it Fuchs ?
Yeah .
Why would it burn him ?
Flare . Maybe he tried to burn it .
[ MacReady ] Maybe he burned himself ...
before it could get to him .
Great ! Now what are we gonna do ?
You go inside . Tell the others we found Fuchs .
We 'll be in as soon as we can .
- Where are we goin ' ? - Up to my shack .
- What the hell for ? - ' Cause when I left , I turned the lights off .
How long have they been out there ?
Forty , forty-five minutes .
We better start closing off the outside doors .
Hey ! All of you come here !
[ Groaning ]
[ Banging ] Open up ! Open up this door ! Open up ! Open up !
Close that door .
- [ Panting ] - Where 's MacReady ?
- I cut him loose of the line up by his shack . - Cut him loose ?
Yeah . We were up checkin ' around his place .
I found this .
Look .
It was stashed in his own oil furnace .
Wind must have dislodged it , but I don 't think he saw me find it .
I made sure I got ahead of him on the towline on the way back .
I cut him loose .
- MacReady ? - He 's one of them .
- When did it get to him ? - I don 't know .
It could have been anytime , anywhere .
- [ Childs ] If it did get to him . - Look , Childs , come on !
- When the lights went out ! - That would have been the perfect time .
Right ! You said guys were missing . And , Windows , where were you ?
Palmer , I told you to shut the fuck up !
Where were you when the lights when out ?
[ Norris ] That 's what it wants : To pit us against each other !
[ Windows ] Guys ! It 's MacReady .
Shh !
[ Handle Squeaking ]
- Let 's open it . - Hell no !
- Do you think he 's changed into one of those things ? - He 's had plenty of time .
- Nothing human could have made it back here without a guideline . - Let 's open it now !
- Why are you so damn anxious to let him in here ? - ' Cause it 's so close !
- May be our best chance to blow it away ! - [ Childs ] No !
- Just let him freeze to death outside . - What if we 're wrong about him ?
- Why , then we 're wrong ! - [ Glass Shattering ]
Supply window !
All right , all right . We got no choice now !
Damn it ! He 's got the keys !
[ MacReady ] What 's goin ' on ? The towline snapped .
[ Nauls ] That 's bullshit , Childs . He knows damn well I cut it .
You 're a dead man , MacReady !
Or a dead whatever the hell you are !
Anyone messes with me and the whole camp goes .
Come on , Childs , burn me .
Put those torches on the floor and back off .
Back off . Way off .
- [ MacReady ] You asshole . - You 'd have done the same thing .
Don 't argue with him .
Where 's the rest ?
So help me , I mean it !
It 's cool , MacReady . It 's cool , man ! Come on !
Yeah , yeah , man . Just relax .
Anybody touches me , and we go .
[ Groans ]
He 's not breathin ' !
Go untie the doc .
Get him in here . And bring the others .
From now on , nobody gets out of my sight .
[ Panting ]
Lay him there .
[ MacReady ] So you sweethearts ...
were about to have yourselves a little lynching party , huh ?
I might just have to put an end to you on general principles , Childs .
Did it occur to the jury that anybody could have stuck some of my clothes up the furnace ?
[ Childs ] We ain 't buying ' that .
[ Copper ] Quit that bickering over there !
Windows , wheel that defibrillator over here !
Put some gel on those paddles !
[ Childs ] You 're gonna have to sleep sometime , MacReady .
I 'm a real light sleeper , Childs .
If anyone tries to wake me ...
Uh-uh .
[ Copper ] Clear !
[ Paddles Shocking ]
- [ Groans ] Clear ! - [ Windows ] Clear .
- [ Thing Roars ] - [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Thing Roaring ]
[ Continues Roaring ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Thing Roaring ]
- We 're on fire , MacReady ! - Get back ! Just wait !
- We 're on fire ! - Just wait !
All right , go !
[ Extinguishers Blasting ]
Windows ! Windows , get in here !
[ Men Coughing ]
[ Hissing ]
You gotta be fuckin ' kidding .
[ Screeching ]
[ Wailing ]
- What do you got in mind , MacReady ? - A little test .
Windows , you and Palmer tie everybody down real tight .
- [ Childs ] What for ? - For your health .
Let 's rush him ! He 's not gonna blow us all up !
No , no , wait a minute . Wait a minute .
Let 's do what Mac says .
I mean , he wasted Norris pretty quick , didn 't he ?
That 's close enough , Clark .
- [ Childs ] He ain 't tying ' me up . - Then I 'll have to kill you .
Then kill me .
I mean it .
[ Cocks Pistol ]
I guess you do .
- This is bullshit , Mac ! - Finish it , Palmer .
They 're dead , Mac !
- Windows ? - Yo ?
You tie up Palmer over here .
We 're gonna draw a little bit of everybody 's blood .
'Cause we 're gonna find out who 's the thing .
Watching Norris in there gave me the idea that ...
maybe every part of him was a whole .
Every little piece was an individual animal ...
with a built-in desire to protect its own life .
You see , when a man bleeds ,
it 's just tissue .
But blood from one of you things won 't obey when it 's attacked .
It 'll try and survive ;
crawl away from a hot needle , say .
[ Banging ]
[ Groans ]
Now you .
That 's good .
All right , move back . Over there .
[ Hot Air Blowing ]
- [ Sizzles ] - [ Sighs ]
I guess you 're okay .
All right , put that on and watch them .
Now I 'll show you what I already know .
[ Sizzles ]
That 's a crock of shit .
Let 's try the Doc and Clark .
[ Sizzling ]
Now Clark .
Then Clark was human , huh ?
Which makes you a murderer , don 't it ?
Palmer now .
This is pure nonsense . It doesn 't prove a thing .
I thought you 'd feel that way , Garry .
You were the only one that could have got to that blood .
We 'll do you last .
[ Blood Screeches ]
Get away from me ! MacReady , burn it !
- [ Screaming ] - What is it ?
[ Childs ] Get him , get him ! Just shoot !
- [ Internal Rumbling ] - [ Flamethrower Misfiring ]
[ Screaming , Indistinct Shouting ]
- MacReady , shoot ! - [ Misfiring Continues ]
- [ Childs ] Get it , Mac ! Get it !
[ Screaming , Shouting ]
Windows ! Blast him !
[ Childs Screaming ] Get me outta here !
[ Roars ]
[ Windows Gasping , Screaming ]
- [ Indistinct Shouting ] - [ Windows Screaming ]
- [ Screaming ] - [ Misfiring ]
- [ Windows Screaming ] - [ Glass Shattering ]
Windows !
[ Thing Roaring ]
- [ Flamethrower Blasting ] - [ Thing Roaring ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Childs Screaming ] Damn ! Get me outta here !
- [ Men Shouting Inside ] - [ Pulls Grenade Pin ]
- [ Groaning ] - [ Garry ] MacReady !
- Get in here ! - Quick , come on ! Hurry up !
It 's coming back ! Burn it ! Burn it , for God 's sake !
- Burn it ! Burn it ! - Hurry up , MacReady !
[ Sizzles ]
[ Hot Air Blowing ]
Let 's do it .
[ Sizzling ]
[ Exhales Slowly ]
[ Childs ] Get me outta here ! Cut me loose !
Cut me the hell ... Come on , get me outta here !
Come on , get me outta here ! Cut me loose , damn it !
[ Sizzles ]
[ Garry ] I know you gentlemen have been through a lot ,
but when you find the time ,
I 'd rather not spend the rest of this winter ...
tied to this fucking couch !
[ Footsteps ]
[ MacReady ] Childs ...
we 're goin ' out to give Blair the test .
If he tries to make it back and we 're not with him ,
burn him .
[ Wind Howling ]
Mac , the door is open .
How 'd he get out ? The door was bolted from the outside .
[ Garry ] Blair ?
[ Nauls ] Hey , Blair ! You down there ?
We got something for ya !
Blair 's been busy out here all by himself .
- What is it ? - Something he 's been making .
It 's a ship of some kind .
He stole the parts from the helicopter .
Smart s.o.b. He put it together piece by piece .
Where was he tryin ' to go ?
Anyplace but here .
Hey , you guys , come here . Come here .
I think I saw Childs outside the main entrance of the camp .
- What 's he doing outside ? - I don 't know .
Got a flare ?
[ Lights Flare ]
He got back inside and blew the generator .
In six hours , it 'll be 100 below in here .
Well , that 's suicide !
Not for that thing .
It wants to freeze now .
It 's got no way outta here . It just wants to go to sleep until the rescue team finds it .
What can we do ? What can we do ?
Whether we make it or not , we can 't let that thing freeze again .
Maybe we 'll just warm things up a little around here .
We 're not gettin outta here alive ...
but neither is that thing .
Generator room .
[ Distant Explosion ]
Generator 's gone .
Anyway we can fix it ?
It 's gone , MacReady .
All right . We gotta bring this whole place right down into the ice .
Garry , plant yours in the old storage room .
Nauls , down by the generator .
[ Bangs On Headlamp ] Oh , God .
[ Gasping ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Groaning Continues ]
[ Indistinct Noise ]
How 's it comin ' in there ?
- I said , " How 's it ... " - [ Indistinct Banging ]
[ MacReady Yelling ]
[ Roars ]
[ Roaring Continues ]
Yeah , fuck you too !
- [ Dynamite Sizzling ] - [ Yelps ]
[ Thing Roaring , Screeching ]
[ Screaming ]
You the only one who made it ?
Not the only one .
Did you kill it ?
Where were you , Childs ?
Thought I saw Blair .
I went out after him ...
and got lost in the storm .
[ Groans ]
[ Laughs ]
Fires got the temperature up all over the camp .
Won 't last long though .
Neither will we .
How will we make it ?
Maybe we shouldn 't .
If you 're worried about me ...
If we 've got any surprises for each other ,
I don 't think we 're in much shape to do anything about it .
Well ... what do we do ?
Why don 't we just ...
wait here for a little while ,
see what happens .
Yeah .
[ Groans ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Laughs ]
Subtitles Provided By Captions , Inc . Los Angeles